today we're meeting a local man who
turned a childhood fascination with
knickknacks into a lifelong passion he's
also turned it into a booming business
Tony has a story in an all new show and
[Music]
tell this is a story knife and it belongs
to my guest today Gary germer Gary is
a professional appraiser and EST State
Liquidator with 30 years of experience in
the business of collecting old stuff
great to meet you now you didn't know this
was a story knife until about 6 months
ago how often is that the case where you
receive an item or you acquire something
and you have to just start digging in
to researching it well and that's why I'm
in this I love the research part of it
and it need you need to research nearly
nearly everything I mean there's stuff
you see regularly I can usually get and
if it's really bad I can usually tell
you right off the bat I see if it's good
I don't necessarily know how good until
we do some homework and what was
the purpose of of a story knife
well the story knife was probably 19th
century and it was a girls toy mainly and
it was often times handed down from
mothers to daughters and they would play a
game similar to Pictionary and this they
would write in the snow and draw in the
snow or in the summer in the mud and tell
a story with it and either they told a
story or they had to guess what story
they were telling and that was the purpose
of it was a toy do you recall the first
thing you came across where you sort of
wanted to keep it
I I think as a kid I used to go through
people's things and get in trouble for
going through their things like what
like well I mean just this and this great
my aunt and uncle I remember their home
they had all kinds of fun things on
their shelves and I was like get away
from there get away from there you know
and now huh now I get to look at it at
what point did you realize you know I
could maybe you know do this for a living
collecting and appraising and being
involved in this world well like
anything else I think it kind of
evolves what do you think in the 30
years years has been maybe like your
greatest find or your biggest surprise
we had a collection we were settling for
a lady that had been her aunts and her
aunt was her aunt's paintings and her
aunt was not famous they were okay but
they were not famous and in amongst it we
found a painting that we sold for
$40,000 you know wow we sold the coffee
table that came in the lady didn't know
I said that's a good table and I was
thinking good when I first saw it $1,000
we sold it for $22,000 for a that's
my current record for a c CFE table at
this point for you is it less about the
object and more about the story behind
the object I love like the a story knife
I love learning the history of it and
the why they made it the fun I find
with collectors has been uh the Hunt is
more fun than the ownership ah you know
finding that last piece to fill out
your collection that's a big deal that's
what they're striving for yeah I told
that to a client once we were talking
about she say well it's
just like marriage then
yeah well the story knife has led to uh
several great stories and it's great to
meet you how much will this sell for do
you think what the it's going to be in
the $500 to $700 range I better put it
down okay good to see you Gary thanks so
much all right oh so NE guy what a NE
guy that's right at my alley yeah his
story is like right outside if you're
leaving the Coliseum like right across
Broadway boom right there uh but he has
a website we uh linked his site to our
site kptv.com but he does like Consignments
appraisals all kinds of things so if
you're at all curious or just going to
I want to see what he's up to you can
find his I'm thinking if we ever can't
find Kim she's lost she's lost in his
store somewhere because that is like
it's fun I mean it's easy to be we shot
this uh Michael obber and I are photographer
and they shot the story came back
and then he actually went back later
and actually made a few purchases he was
became a Believer pretty that's so yeah
so if you want to get a hold of Gary
just on our website put link right because
Kim's already asked Tony and he said
there's a link on our
website special treatment for you young
lady I figured we be let's go to that
3day